Artifact Collection AC
Tufts Archival Research Center
- Manuscript, printed, and book history materials, circa 0100 -- 2007; AC.004.000002
  - Printed materials, 1478 -- 1893; AC.004.009
    This sub-series consists of printed texts dating circa 1478 – 1893. Most of the materials in this series are printed leaves from religious, some with woodblock illustrations, or early texts as well as facsimiles of the same. There are also correspondence, newspapers, and speeches in this series.
    - Leaf from Chaucer's "Canterbury Tales" printed at Westminster, William Caxton, 1478; AC.040.00010 (Box 40)
      From 'Tale of Mellibeus.'
    - Leaf from Nuremburg Chronicle, 1493; AC.012.00002 (Box Small Map Case 2 Drawer 5)
    - Leaf from Terence's "Comediae" with woodcut illustration, circa 1496; AC.020.00009 (Box 20)
    - Printed leaf from Ludolphus de Saxonia with woodblock illustration, circa 1503; AC.040.00008 (Box 40)
    - Printed leaf from the Book of Hours with woodblock illustrations, circa 1505; AC.040.00020 (Box 40)
    - Leaf from "Cronycles of Englande" printed by Wynkyn de Worde, 1515; AC.040.00011 (Box 40)
      Sellers housing with label: "Wynkyn de Worde, 1515. 116 Early Printing. An original folio leaf (two pages), from the 'Cronycles of Englande.' Printed by Wynkyn de Worde in London 1515. Printed in double columns. Black letter. 91/4 x 7 inches. A magnficent study for framing or for study. Rare."
    - Leaf from Boccaccio's "Fall of Princes, Princesses and other Nobles,", 1527; AC.040.00013 (Box 40)
      Second edition, 1527, London. Translator John Lydgate, printer Richard Prynson.
    - Unidentified printed leaf with woodblock illustration, circa 16th century; AC.040.00005 (Box 40)
    - De Successu Evangelii Apud Indos Occidentales, In Nova-Anglia; Epistola (Dr. Mather's letter to Mr. Leusden on Indian affairs), 1683; AC.041.00022 (Box 41)
    - Printed leaves from a Bible, First Book of Maccabees, circa 17th century; AC.040.00012 (Box 40)
    - Proposal and sample sheet for Thomas Bray's "Usurpation and Tyranny, concerning the Usurpations, Wars and Persecutions of the Popes, and Popish Clergy, with reference chiefly to Princes and States, to overturn their government", 1709; AC.020.00001 (Box 20)
    - Epistle of George Fox, printed fragment, 1734; AC.042.00001 (Box Shared 15)
    - Cicero, Cato Major printed by Benjamin Franklin, 1744; AC.011.00017 (Box 11)
    - Leaves from The Yearly Epistle, 1762; AC.020.00010 (Box 20)
    - John Hancock, copy of oration, 1774; AC.041.00017 (Box 41)
    - F. Hawksworth correspondence, 1817; AC.020.00004 (Box 20)
    - The Rural Repository, 1847; AC.020.00002 (Box 20)
    - Basiliense Academy "Certificate", circa 1854; AC.012.00004 (Box Small Map Case 2 Drawer 5)
    - Wallpaper printed over The Opelousas Courier, circa 1863; AC.020.00012 (Box 20)
    - Warrock's Virginia and North Carolina Almanac, 1865; AC.041.00020 (Box 41)
    - Copy of gelatine photo films of newspaper from Siege of Paris, 1870; AC.041.00023 (Box 41)
    - Letter of Christopher Columbus, facsimile, 1875; AC.041.00021 (Box 41)
    - Card Containing James A. Garfield's Inaugural Address, 1881; AC.011.00018 (Box 11)
    - El Porvenir de Bisayas, 10th vol, no. 1790, 1893-04-16; AC.020.00014 (Box Shared 5)
      Newspaper from Iloilo, Phillipines. Issue was found in the 'Ryder Collection of Confederate Archives' in 2011; the Ryder collection was cataloged as part of the WPA in 1939/1940 but in later decades the catalog ( A Calendar of the Ryder Collection of the Confederate Archives at Tufts College 1940) was forgotten and library staff added other materials to the Ryder collection, usually items from the South, from the 18th and 19th century and around the time of the Civil War. Because the newspaper is not part of the original Ryder collection and no relationship to any other former Ryder items could be discerned, the item was moved to the AC collection in spring 2012, Susanne Belovari
    - Pages from an encyclopedia, undated; AC.020.00005 (Box 20)
    - Printed leaves from Bible, undated; AC.040.00004 (Box 40)
  - Prints and painting, circa 1741 -- 2007; AC.004.010
    This sub-series contains illustrative and photographic prints as well as a painting on canvas dating circa 1741 – 2007. The prints include reproduction and original art prints; portraits; and prints depicting citiy scenes.
    No order has been imposed on this subseries.
    - Original prints, circa 1930 -- 2007; AC.027.00002 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 6)
      Original prints removed from map case (room 10), drawer #25. Set of 8 Prints by David Azuz, numbered 36 of 300. 15 prints by B. Gold. 1 Print by Ivan Generalic, numbered 7 of 239 "A Large Rooster on a Stick".
    - Prints and painting, circa 1872 -- 1981; AC.030.00001 (Box 29-30)
      The folder contains prints and a painting on canvas, dating circa 1872 – 1981. The original prints include a print of the Capital Building, undated; a Japanese print, undated; a portrait of Paul Fourmarier, 1934; Gilbert Stewart's George Washington portrait, undated; as well as other prints depicting city scenes and buildings. There are also about seven prints reproducing drawings by Kathe Kollwith, circa 1943.
    - Original prints, undated; AC.030.00003 (Box 29-30)
    - Bolles prints of London, circa 1741 -- 1841; AC.032.00001 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 9)
      This folder contains prints depicting London from several publishers and artists, dating circa 1741 – 1841; printed leaves, undated; a printed portrait of Robert Hermann Schomburgk, dated 1840; a photograph of a statue of the Goddess Athena, undated; and a printed portrait of a man sitting on a bench, undated.
- Portraits, paintings, and sculptures, circa 1863 -- 1970; AC.005.000002; 12 Artifact(s)
  This series contains portraits, paintings, and sculptures dating circa 1863 – 1970. Items depict notable men and literary figures including Francis Parkman (1863); Jack London (1913); and Moby Dick (circa 1970).
  - Plaster of Paris cast of Jack London, 1913; AC.008 (Box 8)
  - Framed portrait of conductor Theodore Thomas, 1901; AC.012.00006a (Box Shared 8)
    This item was found uncatalogued in the stacks in January 2009. Any relationship Theodore Thomas had with Tufts remains unknown.
  - Framed portrait of American historian Francis Parkman, 1863; AC.012.00006b (Box Shared 8)
    Written note of the back of the frame: "Portrait of Francis Parkman given to the Library by Miss Davis". This item was found uncatalogued in the stacks in January 2009. Any relationship Francis Parkman had with Tufts remains unknown. The item was originally framed by Dodge, Collier and Perkins [115 Washington St., Boston]
  - Framed portrait of unknown student in graduation cap and gown, circa 1870 -- 1929; AC.012.00007 (Box Shared 8)
    This date is approximate. This item was found uncatalogued in the stacks in January 2009.
  - Framed painting of unknown man, circa 1900; AC.012.00008 (Box Shared 8)
    This date is approximate. This painting was found uncataloged and wrapped in brown paper on top of the special collection shelving in the Winter of 2009.
  - Unidentified male bust, possibly Edgar Allan Poe, circa 20th century; AC.017.00017 (Box 45)
  - Unidentified male profile bust (metal), AC.017.00020 (Box Shared 10)
  - Unidentified male bust, undated; AC.017.00021 (Box 17)
    Physical condition.
  - Henry David Thoreau frieze, 1970; AC.017.00022 (Box 18)
    The inscriptions read, " Any man more right than his neighbor constitutes a majority of one. Henry D. Thoreau". Sculptured probably by Tunison, G.R.G., dates are approximate (19)70.
  - Moby Dick frieze, 1970; AC.017.00023 (Box 12)
  - Photograph of a group of men in suits, circa 1890 -- 1900; AC.029.00003 (Box 29-30)
    These dates are approximate. Appears to be a photograph of a club or fraternity. Item was found uncataloged in the stacks in the spring of 2009.
    photographic print
  - Photograph of man in suit, circa 1930s -- 1950s; AC.029.00002 (Box 29-30)
    Dates are approximate. Inscription reads "To my classmate and friend Bill." Item found uncataloged in the stacks in the spring of 2009.
- Other artifacts, circa 1600 -- 1950; AC.006; 7 Artifact(s)
  This series contains artifacts dating circa 1600 – 1950 accrued by Digital Collections and Archives over time. These artifacts include a bamboo pipe flute, a cannon ball, memorabilia from the National Congress for the League of Nations, research notes on the history of apples, and a silver cup.
  - Peace puzzle, circa 1915; AC.017.00004 (Box Shared 9)
  - League to Enforce Peace delegate pin for the National Congress for a League of Nations, 1919; AC.017.00008 (Box Shared 9)
  - Small silver cup, enscribed with "D. R. 1891-1912", circa 1912; AC.017.00011 (Box Shared 9)
  - Bamboo pipe flute, 1950; AC.017.00013 (Box Shared 9)
    Top tray. Donated by Amos Booth (or Howard Cook).
    Donald and Charlotte MacJannet, papers
  - Cannon ball, circa 17th -- 19th century; AC.017.00019 (Box Shared 10)
  - Research notes on the history of apples, circa 1870s -- 1920s; AC.037.00002 (Box 37)
    This date is approximate. The item could be from the 1870's to 1920's. The item is very fragile.